i-parcel.com 2017-11-13

# i-parcel Online Privacy Notice | UPS i-parcel

Effective Date: ** ** January 25, 2016

i-parcel respects your concerns about privacy.  This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we obtain about consumers via [www.i-parcel.com](http://www.i-parcel.com/) and on our merchant partners’ e-commerce checkout web pages.  This Privacy Notice also describes how we may use the information, with whom we may share it, and the measures we take to safeguard the personal information we collect.  In addition, we tell you how you can ask us to (i) access or change the personal information we maintain about you, (ii) withdraw consent you previously provided to us, (iii) refrain from sending you certain communications, and (iv) answer questions you may have about our privacy practices.  This Privacy Notice does not apply to our corporate parent, United Parcel Service, Inc., which is subject to its own Privacy Notice that can be found [here](http://www.ups.com/content/us/en/resources/ship/terms/privacy.html?WT.svl=Footer).

You can view certain country-specific information by clicking [here](https://www.ups.com/content/us/en/resources/ship/terms/privacy.html).

Select one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

  * _Information We Obtain_
  * _How We Use The Information We Obtain_
  * _Interest-Based Advertising_
  * _Information We Share_
  * _Your Options_
  * _Notice to California Residents_
  * _Non-i-parcel Store Places and Services_
  * _How We Protect Personal Information_
  * _Updates To Our Privacy Notice_
  * _How To Contact Us_

**Information We Obtain**

The types of personal information that we may obtain include:

  * Contact information (such as name, email address and telephone number);
  * Shipping information (such as shipping-related contact details like the shipper’s and consignee’s name, physical address, email address and telephone number);
  * Information regarding the products you’ve ordered;
  * Government-issued identifiers such as your Tax identification number or national identification number when required by law to facilitate the delivery;
  * Payment information (including payment card details or online payment services number and billing address) and financial information (such as bank account number); and
  * User name and password used to access your i-parcel account.

In addition, when you visit our website, we may collect certain information by automated means.  The information collected in this manner may include IP address, unique device identifier, browser characteristics, device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, information on actions taken, and dates and times of activity.  We also may collect this information when you visit our merchant partners’ checkout pages.

When you visit our website or our merchant partners’ checkout pages, this information may be collected through “cookies,” web beacons and other automated means.  A “cookie” is a text file that websites send to a visitor’s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser.  A “web beacon,” also known as a spotlight tag, Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server. Through these automated collection efforts, i-parcel obtains and stores “clickstream data” and other information to tell us about our visitors’ usage.

We also may use third-party web analytics services on our website, such as those of Google Analytics.  These service providers help us analyze how visitors use the site.  The information obtained for this purpose (including your IP address and other information collected by automated means) will be disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers.  To learn about opting out of Google Analytics, please [click here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies or how to restrict or disable certain types of cookies.  Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our site.  Both we and others (such as our advertising networks) may collect personal information about our visitors’ online activities, over time and across third-party websites, when using our site.

**How We Use The Information We Obtain**

We may use the information we obtain to:

  * Process and collect payments;
  * Provide customer support and respond to and communicate with you about your requests, questions and comments
  * Communicate with you about products and services that may interest you;
  * Establish and manage your accounts;
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our sales, marketing and advertising; analyzing and enhancing our products, services and Sites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * Perform data analyses (including market and consumer research, trend analysis and financial analysis);
  * Protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities; and
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements and our policies.

In addition, we use information collected online through cookies, web beacons and other automated means for purposes such as (i) customizing our users’ visits to our websites, (ii) delivering content (including advertising) tailored to our users’ interests and the manner in which our users browse our sites, and (iii) managing our businesses.  We also use this information to help diagnose technical and service problems, administer our sites, identify users of our sites, and gather demographic information about our users.  We use clickstream data to determine usage patterns and how we may tailor our sites to better meet the needs of our users.

i-parcel also may use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

**Interest-Based Advertising**

On our website, both i-parcel and certain third parties may collect information about your online activities for use in providing you with advertising about products and services tailored to your individual interests.  This section of our Privacy Notice provides details and explains how to exercise your choices.

You may see certain ads on other websites because i-parcel participates in advertising networks.  Ad networks allow us to target our messaging to users through demographic, interest-based and contextual means.  These networks track your online activities over time by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of cookies, web server logs and web beacons.  The networks use this information to show you advertisements that may be tailored to your individual interests.  The information ad networks may collect includes information about your visits to websites that participate in the relevant advertising networks, such as the pages or advertisements you view and the actions you take on the websites.  This data collection may take place both on our site and on third-party websites that participate in the ad networks.  This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.  To learn about how to opt out of this ad network interest-based advertising, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Our site is not designed to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers.

**Information We Share   **

i-parcel does not sell or otherwise share personal information about you, except as described in this Privacy Notice.  i-parcel shares personal information with third parties, including UPS affiliates, who perform services on our behalf based on our instructions.  These third parties are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements.  Any personal information we obtain from the merchant partner checkout web page is shared back with that merchant.

i-parcel also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena); (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities; or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.  i-parcel reserves the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation).

**Your Options**

You may choose not to receive marketing email communications from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in our marketing emails.  To learn more about how to opt out of ad network interest-based advertising, please visit the consumer opt-out page [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).  In addition, as required by law, you may object at any time on legitimate grounds and free of charge to the processing of your personal information, and we will apply your preferences going forward.

**Notice to California Residents   **

To the extent required by applicable law, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

**Access and Correction**

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to obtain access to personal information we maintain about you by contacting us as indicated in the “How To Contact Us” section of this Privacy Notice.  To help protect your privacy and maintain security, we will take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the information.  In addition, if you believe that personal information we maintain about you is inaccurate, subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request that we correct or amend the information by contacting us as indicated below.

**Non-i-parcel Places and Services**

For your convenience and information, the site may contain links to non-i-parcel places that may be operated by companies not affiliated with i-parcel.  These companies may have their own privacy policies or notices, which we strongly suggest you review.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any non-i-parcel places or services.

**Data Transfers**

We may transfer the personal information we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information originally was collected.  Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information.  When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Notice and in accordance with applicable law.  We use contractual protections for the transfer of personal information among various jurisdictions (including, for example, the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses).

**How We Protect Personal Information**

i-parcel maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

**Updates To Our Privacy Notice**

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices.  i-parcel will post a prominent notice on our site to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Notice and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.

**How To Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, please contact us by email at privacy@ups.com

**i-parcel: Privacy Notice – EEA Addendum**

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the following additional EEA-specific provisions apply to our processing of your personal information.  For EEA residents, the provisions of this EEA Addendum prevail over conflicting provisions in the Privacy Notice.

Relevant Data Controller

i-parcel Limited, established in the UK, is the data controller. **  
**

Information We Obtain

We process names, email addresses and telephone numbers of others to whom we are asked to send information on the assumption that the person who provided the information obtained it in accordance with applicable law. If this assumption is incorrect, please do not ask us to send information to third parties on your behalf.

In accordance with applicable law, we may obtain your consent separately before collecting information by automated means using cookies or similar devices. To learn more about the cookies and similar devices we use, please see our Cookies Policy.

How We Use The Information We Obtain

If we use your information for marketing purposes (as described in the Privacy Notice), you may object to the use of your information for such purposes, easily and free of charge, at the time of its collection and at the time of receipt of each marketing communication. We will honour your request. We will not provide your information to third parties for marketing purposes without your prior consent.

Access and Correction

In addition to the right to access and correct your personal information, you have the right to have your information blocked or deleted in accordance with applicable law.
